<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-1.0.0.xsd">
  <properties>
    <title>Changes to the Middleware Project</title>
    <author email="Thomas.W.Narock@nasa.gov">Tom Narock</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    
     <release version="1.2.0" date="2012-03-01" description="Version 1.2.0 Release">
      <action dev="narock" type="fix">
		Fixed bug GetGranuleURLs. A table that was already in UTC was being incorrectly 
		converted to UTC again by a query.
      </action>
     </release>
     
     <release version="1.1.9" date="2011-06-01" description="Version 1.1.9 Release">
      <action dev="narock" type="fix">
		Fixed bug in atSameTime search. Previously, the SQL query was incorrect and finding
		times of availability, not times of overlap.
      </action>
     </release>
     
     <release version="1.1.8" date="2011-05-13" description="Version 1.1.8 Release">
      <action dev="narock" type="add">
		Added code to check if start date was after stop date. If yes, then dates are reversed
		and a warning is printed to the response message.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="add">
		Added code to look for planets (and hence Earth-based spacecraft) when HCI search is conducted.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
		Updated how temporary tables are constructed. Use integer productID (resource_id) instead of
		string productID (spase_id) as it makes the queries faster.  All classes interacting with temporary
		tables were updated accordingly.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
		Updated the SQL query that returns granule information. Now includes start/stop time of temp_final
		table, which makes the query significantly faster.
      </action>
     </release>
     
     <release version="1.1.7" date="2011-03-16" description="Version 1.1.7 Release">
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
	Added more SQL escaping/validation.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="add">
	Added query forwarding for ResourceID and ObservatoryRegion.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
	Updated handling of Regions in middleware. Regions are now expanded and all sub-regions are also searched, 
	e.g. Earth.Magnetosphere will search Magnetosphere, Magnetosphere.Main, and Magnetosphere.Tail
      </action>
     </release>
    
     <release version="1.1.6" date="2011-02-16" description="Version 1.1.6 Release">
      <action dev="alaimo" type="update">
	Updated how cancel file is created and handled.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.1.5" date="2011-02-14" description="Version 1.1.5 Release">
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
	Updated the xslt transform of SPASE XML to owl.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.1.4" date="2011-02-04" description="Version 1.1.4 Release">
      <action dev="alaimo" type="update">
	Updated the previous requirement that the Execute class would produce a PHP error page
	in the event that there was an error during the query execution.  The end result is the
	redirection to the PHP response pages which will only display the error message, contact form
	and a back button at present.	
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.3" date="2011-01-31" description="Version 1.1.3 Release">
      <action dev="narock" type="fix">
        Fixed StatsPlots servlet handling of input file. Previously the servlet did not account 
        for api call where the response files have different names than they do when generated 
        from the web interface.  Thus, this servlet only worked for the web interface. This has
        been resolved.
      </action>
      <action dev="alaimo" type="fix">
        Updated Granules query to fix issue with SQL DISTINCT. Previously the DISITINCT was in
        the wrong place in the query, which caused results not to be shown for products that 
        are from multiple instruments.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.1.2" date="2011-01-28" description="Version 1.1.2 Release">
      <action dev="alaimo" type="update">
        Updated SPASEQL dependency to 1.6.5, which adds support for Keyword queries.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.1.1" date="2011-01-24" description="Version 1.1.1 Release">
      <action dev="narock" type="add">
        Added check on limit value.  If user requests a limit greater than 2000 through the api then the limit is
        automatically truncated to 2000.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
        SPASEQL dependency updated to 1.6.4, which allows SPASEQL query schema to be specified as input variable. Removes the 
        dependency that the spaseql server (home of the schema) had to be online for queries to validate.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2011-01-19" description="Version 1.1.0 Release">
      <action dev="alaimo" type="update">
        Updated servlets to work with new php results pages.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="remove">
        Removed external jars in resources/lib and made part of Maven dependencies.
      </action>
       <action dev="narock" type="update">
        SPASEQL dependency updated to 1.6.4, which allows SPASEQL query schema to be specified as input variable. Removes the 
        dependency that the spaseql server (home of the schema) had to be online for queries to validate.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.0.4" date="2010-11-04" description="Version 1.0.4 Release">
      <action dev="alaimo" type="update">
        Updated query results code to work with new php results pages.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="remove">
        Removed unused code from older versions.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.0.2" date="2010-11-04" description="Version 1.0.2 Release">
      <action dev="alaimo" type="fix">
        Fixed resourceType=granule search that was mistakenly broken in previous release.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
        Updated how SPASEQL schema is handled. Now read from SPASEQL website (HTTP) instead of from local file.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2010-09-28" description="Bug Fixes and Functionality Additions">
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
        Updated Inventory (AvailableData.java) to now have start/stop times as per change in SPASEQL schema.
      </action>
      <action dev="alaimo" type="update">
        Updated response page to now include new Contact Form.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="fix">
        Fixed the way queries, which do not request granules in the results, are handled.
      </action>
      <action dev="narock" type="fix">
        Fixed how start/stop times are retrieved from the database for products. No need to get all granule intervals. 
        Now use min and max functions.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.0.0" date="2010-09-15" description="First release">
      <action dev="narock" type="update">
        Initial Release.
      </action>
    </release>
    
  </body>
</document>
